Yefan Zhi

yefanzhi@design.upenn.edu

https://psl.design.upenn.edu/yefan-zhi/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/yefanzhi/

Yefan Zhi is a second-year Ph.D. student in Architecture at the University of Pennsylvania. His research optimizes the energy and material efficiency of architectural structures from design-for-manufacturing perspectives. His work extensively exploits computational geometry and graph algorithms for automating fabrication rationalization and enabling fabrication-oriented design. Yefan is a member of the Polyhedral Structures Laboratory (PSL) concentrating on advancing structural and architectural geometry and construction technologies.

Education

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Architecture, University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia, PA, US

Master of Science in Design - MSD, Architecture, University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia, PA, US

Bachelor of Architecture - BArch, Architecture, Tsinghua University Beijing, China

Aug 2016 - Jun 2021

Aug 2016 - Jun 2020

Experience

Polyhedral Structures Laboratory, University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia, PA, US

- PhD Fellow, Full-Time. National Science Foundation (NSF) Future Manufacturing Research Grant

- Research Assistant, Full-Time. Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) Grant

Jul 2023 - Present Sep 2022 - Jun 2023

People's Architecture Office Beijing, China

- Research Intern, Full-Time

Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

Journal Papers (Peer-reviewed)

[J2] Designing 3D-Printed Concrete Structures with Scaled Fabrication Models *Yefan Zhi*, Teng Teng, Masoud Akbarzadeh

Architectural Intelligence 2024

[J1] Research on the Villagers' Behavior Characteristics in Rural Area: Analysis Using Spatio-Temporal Data from Wi-Fi and Surveillance Video

Yefan Zhi, Ziyu Huang, Weixin Huang Urban, Environment, Design (UED) 2023 in Chinese, on Cover

Conference Papers (Peer-reviewed)

[C7] Integrated and Tailored Thermal Insulation through Gradient Multimaterial Additive Manufacturing for Masonry Architectural Components

Teng Teng, Yefan Zhi, Masoud Akbarzadeh

Association for Computer Aided Design in Architecture (ACADIA) Annual Conference 2024 Calgary, Canada

[C6] The Effect of Post-tensioning on the Behavior of Small-Scale 3D-Printed Concrete Beams

Damon Bolhassani, Fahimeh Yavartanoo, Javier Tapia, Masoud Akbarzadeh, Maximilian E. Ororbia, Hua Chai, *Yefan Zhi*, Mylene Bernard, Leon Trousset, Karolina Pajak, Blaise Waligun, Paul Kassabian International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures (IASS) Annual Symposia 2024 *Zurich, Switzerland*

[C5] Experimental and Numerical Study of a Funicular Concrete Beam Prototype

Maximilian Ororbia, Hua Chai, Yefan Zhi, Pouria Vakhshouri, Jorge Chacon, Joseph Yost, Mathias Bernhard, Fahimeh Yavartanoo, Javier Tapia, Damon Bolhassani, Mylene Bernard, Leon Trousset, Karolina Pajak, Blaise Waligun, Paul Kassabian, Masoud Akbarzadeh

International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures (IASS) Annual Symposia 2024 Zurich, Switzerland

[C4] Design Approach for a Post-tensioned Funicular Concrete Beam

Hua Chai, Maximilian Ororbia, Yefan Zhi, Ryan Welch, Billie Faircloth, Fahimeh Yavartanoo, Damon Bolhassani, Masoud Akbarzadeh

International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures (IASS) Annual Symposia 2024 Zurich, Switzerland

[C3] Diamanti: 3D-Printed, Post-tensioned Concrete Canopy

Masoud Akbarzadeh, Hua Chai, *Yefan Zhi*, Maximilian E. Ororbia, Teng Teng, Mathias Bernhard, Damon Bolhassani, Fahimeh Yavartanoo, Javier Tapia, Karolina Pajak, Mylene Bernard, Leon Trousset, Paul Kassabian, Blaise Waligun FABRICATE 2024 *Copenhagen*, *Denmark*

- [C2] Local Optimization of Self-Supporting Shell Structures in 3D Printing: a Skeleton Method Yefan Zhi, Hua Chai, Teng Teng, Masoud Akbarzadeh International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures (IASS) Annual Symposia 2023 Melbourne, Australia
- [C1] Continuous Multi-Filament 3D Printing for Tension-Compression Structure Components Teng Teng, Yefan Zhi, Kun-Hao Yu, Shu Yang, Masoud Akbarzadeh International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures (IASS) Annual Symposia 2023 Melbourne, Australia

Preprints

[P1] Single-Nozzle Multi-Filament System with Active Mixing for High-Fidelity Multimaterial Additive Manufacturing

Teng Teng, Yefan Zhi, Masoud Akbarzadeh

Theses

A Wi-Fi and Video Data-Based Study on Spatial-Temporal Characteristics of Rural Space Behavior

Yefan Zhi, Advised by Weixin Huang

Bachelor of Architecture thesis 2021, Tsinghua University Beijing, China, in Chinese

Forming Norms in a Small Community: a Sociological Study of Birdwatching

Yefan Zhi, Advised by Yue Du

Bachelor of Arts in Sociology thesis 2020, Tsinghua University Beijing, China, in Chinese

Software

Ovenbird, A cross-scale shell printing slicer and optimizer *Yefan Zhi*, Hua Chai, Teng Teng, Masoud Akbarzadeh

Sep 2022 - Present

BibGallery, A light, simple literature management library on Python *Yefan Zhi*

Dec 2022 - Present

Exhibitions

Advanced Research Projects Agency–Energy (ARPA-E) Energy Innovation Summit 2023 Washington, DC, US Apr 2023

- Technology showcase, part of University of Pennsylvania

Association for Computer Aided Design in Architecture (ACADIA) Conference 2022 Philadelphia, PA, US

Oct 2022

- Faculty research exhibition, part of Polyhedral Structures Laboratory
- Student work exhibition, part of Master of Science in Design program

Weitzman School Year End Show 2022, University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia, PA, US

May 2022

- Student work exhibition, part of Master of Science in Design program